<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/version2/remiXML2.1.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/caramessina/remiXML/master/version2/visualize_remiXML2.1.xsl"?>
<remiXML>
    <metadata>
        <originalTitle>Title of original text</originalTitle>
        <originalAuthor>Original author's name</originalAuthor> <!-- There might be multiple authors. -->
        <documentTitle>Title of document</documentTitle>
        <documentAuthor ID="CM1">Your name</documentAuthor>
        <!-- Don't forget to use your ID if there are multiple document authors. -->
    </metadata>
    <original>
        <p><closeRead ID="CR1" type="critique">The full or excerpted original text will go in this section.</closeRead> For the most part, I (the
            instructor) will be providing you with a template with the excerpts. This way, you will
            not need to copy and paste or transcribe anything; instead, you can <question ID="Q1"
                type="critical">focus on reading and marking up the original text.</question></p>
        <p>The "p" element, or the element that is surrounding this text, <expand ID="E1" type="background">stands for paragraph.</expand> It
            might also be used for stanzas in poetry. If there is poetry, the "l" element can mark
            up the lines. When you go to visualize your <replace ID="RP3" type="verb">marked up</replace> document using the red play button
            at the top of Oxygen (so when you turn your XML file into an HTML file to view in your
            browser), you will be able to see the difference between a line and a paragraph.</p>
        <p><l>This is a line surrounded by a paragraph <replace ID="RP1" type="noun">element</replace></l>
            <l>This is a continued line.</l>
            <l>Poetry is fun.</l>
            <l>Too bad I am not very good at it.</l></p>
        <p>Now that we've talked a bit about what the "original" element tag is for and how to use
            the paragraph and line elements, it's time to dig into the fun question: how do we mark
            up texts?</p>
        <p>In this schema, there are five main elements you will use to mark up texts: closeRead,
            expand, question, replace, and restory.</p>
        <p>Let's use the closeRead example to talk a bit about how to structure your elements as you
            mark up the original text. The closeRead element is used for more of the classic,
            traditional close readings. When you are looking to mark up and close read a moment in
            the text, you will highlight the moment that you are close reading and wrap it in the
            "closeRead" (case sensitive, like passwords) element by using a start tag. You can
            highlight and wrap moments in the text by clicking Command + E (for Macs); then begin to
            type out the element and Oxygen should provide suggestions for you. </p>
        <p><closeRead type="description" ID="CR3">In the closeRead element (like the other elements),</closeRead> you have multiple TYPES of close
            reading to choose from. You MUST choose one of these types. When you type the "type"
            attribute, the equal sign, and the quotation marks, Oxygen is smart enough to give you a
            list of options to choose from! There is even an explanation of each type of close
            reading. Thanks, Oxygen! You will also notice there are two other attributes: the "ID"
            and the "daID." The ID attribute is a requirement; you make this value, however, and you
            must make sure the ID in this section matches with the corresponding ID in the "play"
            section. Otherwise, you will not be connecting the moment you're marking up with your
            actual close reading analysis. </p>
        <p>Also, you will notice that when you click the red play button and transform this document
            from an XML to an HTML file, your HTML file that pops up in your browser will have
            colors all over it! The colors indicate to your reader of the document which moments you
            have marked up and how you have marked it up. When your reader clicks on the colored
            font, your actual comments will pop up! Here are the elements that the different colors
            represent:</p>
        <p><question type="content" ID="Q2">purple means question</question>
            <l><expand type="description" ID="E2">pink means expand</expand></l>
            <l><closeRead ID="CR2" type="pattern">blue means close read</closeRead></l>
            <l><replace ID="RP2" type="noun">orange means replace</replace></l>
            <l><restory ID="RS2" type="AU">green means restory</restory></l>
        </p>
        <p>You will also probably notice that reading this XML document can be a bit tough because
            there are a bunch of elements marking up the text. This is why the HTML document is
            important! It will be easier to read AND the "play" moments will be connected to the
            moments in the "original" text. When you view the HTML document, you now know what my
            interventions in this text have said.</p>
    </original>
    <play>
        <closeRead REF="CR1">CLOSE READ</closeRead>
        <closeRead REF="CR2">There is repetition happening, which means the author (myself) is
            emphasizing something important! Also I could just be listing. </closeRead>
        <closeRead REF="CR3">Confirms that the closeRead as an example through the use of the parenthetical side note </closeRead>
        <expand REF="E1">The origin of inspiration for using the "p" element comes from HTML's "p" element, which represents a paragraph, as well.</expand>
        <expand REF="E2">It's not a real pink, but more of a muted red. Because every color looks
            muted when its applied to Times New Roman font.</expand>
        <question REF="Q1">What does it mean to "read" and "mark up" a text? How do we define these
            actions? </question>
        <question REF="Q2">What is "purple?"</question>
        <replace REF="RP1">start tag and end tag</replace>
        <replace REF="RP2">replace means green</replace>
        <replace REF="RP3">XML formatted</replace>
        <restory REF="RS2">In an alternate universe, blue might mean replace!</restory>
    </play>
</remiXML>
